<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Automation on CINAQ</title>
    <link>/categories/automation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Automation on CINAQ</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 13:37:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/automation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Low-Ops Platform: The 7-Star Hotel for Apps</title>
      <link>/blog/2023/05/18/low-ops-platform-the-7-star-hotel-for-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 13:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2023/05/18/low-ops-platform-the-7-star-hotel-for-apps/</guid>
      <description>In the world of technology, efficiency and convenience are paramount. Just like how you would prefer to stay in a luxurious 7-star hotel during your holidays, IT professionals and app developers also seek an environment where everything is taken care of seamlessly. This desire for a hassle-free experience is what makes a low-ops platform akin to a 7-star hotel for apps. While traditional app delivery may resemble renting a low-budget apartment, where you have more freedom but a lot on your plate, a low-ops platform offers a superior alternative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The missing link between Reminders and Calendar app on iOS</title>
      <link>/blog/2022/11/22/the-missing-link-between-reminders-and-calendar-app-on-ios/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 13:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022/11/22/the-missing-link-between-reminders-and-calendar-app-on-ios/</guid>
      <description>My obsession to live by my calendar meant I was always on the lookout for optimizing my agenda workflow. The Apple ecosystem works very nicely together. And don&amp;rsquo;t forget the fact usability is top-notch and well-thought-out. My quest to find the perfect productivity setup has come full circle: started with Apple apps, tried many third-party tools, and finally, we are back to square one with Apple apps. But now with a tiny modern enhancement.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
