<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on CINAQ</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on CINAQ</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A shortcut to owning an internal developers platform</title>
      <link>/blog/2024/08/13/a-shortcut-to-owning-an-internal-developers-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:13:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2024/08/13/a-shortcut-to-owning-an-internal-developers-platform/</guid>
      <description>Internal developer platform (IDP) is trending lately as it catches IT leaders’ attention. The quest for never-ending efficiency evolved from centralized sysadmin teams to decentralized DevOps, SRE and platforms. All with the ultimate goal to enable rapid value delivery. This is critical in today’s fast-paced world where time to market is crucial for business success.
What is an internal developer platform? An IDP is like a town square where developers who own applications or want to own applications come together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HashiCorp&#39;s Shift to BSL v1.1 and its Effect on PaaS</title>
      <link>/blog/2023/08/14/hashicorps-shift-to-bsl-v1.1-and-its-effect-on-paas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 00:13:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2023/08/14/hashicorps-shift-to-bsl-v1.1-and-its-effect-on-paas/</guid>
      <description>As of August 10, HashiCorp made an important announcement regarding a significant shift in its licensing strategy. The transition from the Mozilla Public License 2.0 (MPL 2.0) to the Business Source License version 1.1 (BSL v1.1) has generated considerable discussions and anticipation within the technology community. In this post, we aim to shed light on the implications of this change, not only for our team but also for companies like heroku, fly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy Mendix app to Kubernetes without corrupting your data</title>
      <link>/blog/2023/06/05/deploy-mendix-app-to-kubernetes-without-corrupting-your-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 13:37:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2023/06/05/deploy-mendix-app-to-kubernetes-without-corrupting-your-data/</guid>
      <description>Deploying Mendix apps in Kubernetes can be more complex than anticipated, often leading to potential issues like data corruption. This article delves into the specific challenges of running Mendix apps in a cloud-native environment. It examines the risks posed by concurrent versions, the importance of the leader-workers model, and the impact of deployment strategies. Furthermore, it explores the introduction of Mendix for private cloud and the mitigation techniques that can be employed to ensure a smooth and secure deployment process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low-Ops Platform: The 7-Star Hotel for Apps</title>
      <link>/blog/2023/05/18/low-ops-platform-the-7-star-hotel-for-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 13:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2023/05/18/low-ops-platform-the-7-star-hotel-for-apps/</guid>
      <description>In the world of technology, efficiency and convenience are paramount. Just like how you would prefer to stay in a luxurious 7-star hotel during your holidays, IT professionals and app developers also seek an environment where everything is taken care of seamlessly. This desire for a hassle-free experience is what makes a low-ops platform akin to a 7-star hotel for apps. While traditional app delivery may resemble renting a low-budget apartment, where you have more freedom but a lot on your plate, a low-ops platform offers a superior alternative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The missing link between Reminders and Calendar app on iOS</title>
      <link>/blog/2022/11/22/the-missing-link-between-reminders-and-calendar-app-on-ios/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 13:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022/11/22/the-missing-link-between-reminders-and-calendar-app-on-ios/</guid>
      <description>My obsession to live by my calendar meant I was always on the lookout for optimizing my agenda workflow. The Apple ecosystem works very nicely together. And don&amp;rsquo;t forget the fact usability is top-notch and well-thought-out. My quest to find the perfect productivity setup has come full circle: started with Apple apps, tried many third-party tools, and finally, we are back to square one with Apple apps. But now with a tiny modern enhancement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mendix SVG Hunt</title>
      <link>/blog/2022/10/20/mendix-svg-hunt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 13:37:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022/10/20/mendix-svg-hunt/</guid>
      <description>Today a client reached out to me with a mysterious case where the build pipeline of his Mendix app started to fail. He has just upgraded his app to Mendix 7.23.33 but was surprised it was not very smooth. As always I&amp;rsquo;m intrigued by out-of-ordinary problems. And this one turned out quite interesting.
The error As with most issues, it starts with a huge stacktrace. You can find this stacktrace in the appendix A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Side effects of traveling frequently</title>
      <link>/blog/2022/10/10/side-effects-of-traveling-frequently/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 13:37:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022/10/10/side-effects-of-traveling-frequently/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re someone who travels frequently, or even if you&amp;rsquo;re the type of person who just likes to travel, it&amp;rsquo;s very likely that you&amp;rsquo;ve experienced some side effects from your trips. But don&amp;rsquo;t worry! Most of these side effects are positive in nature. Some are even downright amazing! Here are some of the most common side effects of traveling frequently:
The social effects Traveling is one of the best things you can do for your mental and physical health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ultimate distributed workstation setup</title>
      <link>/blog/2022/10/05/the-ultimate-distributed-workstation-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 13:37:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022/10/05/the-ultimate-distributed-workstation-setup/</guid>
      <description>For my multi-workstation setup, I often need my files synchronized across multiple devices. As you can imagine not all files must be synchronized across. To control that I use an ignore list similar to the .gitignore concept in git and there is a git clean command that removes untracked files. I needed that but for Syncthing.
Requirements To explain my problem I will start with the context. My primary use case is that I want access to all my files at all times on different devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mysterious Ipad screen mirror app detected by PSI Secure browser</title>
      <link>/blog/2022/08/28/mysterious-ipad-screen-mirror-app-detected-by-psi-secure-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 13:37:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022/08/28/mysterious-ipad-screen-mirror-app-detected-by-psi-secure-browser/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re in a rush for the solution, jump to the bottom of this page.
 Recently I had my CKS (Certified Kubernetes Security Specialist) exam via the PSI platform. A few weeks earlier when I scheduled the exam I made sure to run the system check because I had troubles with these in the past with my macbook (OSX). I don&amp;rsquo;t recall which exam platform it was.
10 minutes before the scheduled exam I opened the PSI portal to start the check-in process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is the Mendix Basic Package for me?</title>
      <link>/blog/2022/06/04/is-the-mendix-basic-package-for-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 00:13:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022/06/04/is-the-mendix-basic-package-for-me/</guid>
      <description>Mendix introduced the Basic package back in September 2021. It has been one of the most anticipated moves around licensing because there were Free apps, the free tier which mostly enabled hobby projects or newcomers to try out Mendix. The second option was simply: enterprise sales.
With the Basic Package, Mendix tries to close the gap between free and enterprise. Which as you might have guessed would be small businesses, more demanding hobby projects, or startups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reduce screen time as Developer</title>
      <link>/blog/2021/09/04/reduce-screen-time-as-developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 01:11:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021/09/04/reduce-screen-time-as-developer/</guid>
      <description>Developers spend countless hours in front of computer screens. The majority of professions today require interactions with computers. As if that&amp;rsquo;s not enough, it extends further into our private lives in this digital age. Even consumer products like iOS and Android devices have built-in metrics to keep track of your screen time. In this article, we explain why it&amp;rsquo;s essential to reduce screen time and give you ideas on how to do it as an IT engineer; and, in parallel, protect your eyes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You have built a Mendix app, now what?</title>
      <link>/blog/2021/04/13/you-have-built-a-mendix-app-now-what/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 00:13:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021/04/13/you-have-built-a-mendix-app-now-what/</guid>
      <description>Recently the first Mendix book was published. It was titled Building Low-Code Applications with Mendix: Discover best practices and expert techniques to simplify enterprise web development by Bryan Kenneweg, Imran Kasam, and Micah McCullen. It guides the reader to become an application developer on the Mendix platform. This book inspired me also to contribute to growing and educating this unique low-code community.
What drives me? I joined the Mendix company in 2012, fresh out of university.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your business logic is the weakest link in Low-Code security</title>
      <link>/blog/2020/08/09/your-business-logic-is-the-weakest-link-in-low-code-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 13:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020/08/09/your-business-logic-is-the-weakest-link-in-low-code-security/</guid>
      <description>Over the past 5 years interest in low-code increased 100 folds according to Google Trends: This correlates with human psychology eager to optimise for efficiency in everything and building software solutions is no exception. As programming is becoming easier and more accessible, in the future, anyone should be able solve their own information automation challenges. Low-code is a relatively new movement that tries to enable those citizen developers with the right tooling lowering the barrier to build applications without writing traditional code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Highly available Kubernetes with batteries for small business</title>
      <link>/blog/2020/05/25/highly-available-kubernetes-with-batteries-for-small-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 13:37:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020/05/25/highly-available-kubernetes-with-batteries-for-small-business/</guid>
      <description>Kindie (Kubernetes Individual) is an opinionated Kubernetes cluster setup for individuals or small business. Batteries included so that you can hit the ground running and add production workload in no time.
Target audience Sysadmin, DevOps, Cloud engineer with Linux and Kubernetes experience looking to build a Kubernetes cluster for production usage with bells and whistles focussed on web workloads. You should be able to have the cluster ready in a few hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speed up docker builds with distcc, ccache and kubernetes</title>
      <link>/blog/2020/05/10/speed-up-docker-builds-with-distcc-ccache-and-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 13:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020/05/10/speed-up-docker-builds-with-distcc-ccache-and-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>For a recent project I had to write my own Orthanc plugin. To build this plugin I needed to build Orthanc from source. The official docker-images are assembled based on pre-built binaries. So I could not use them.
Orthanc Dockerfile The first step is create a Dockerfile that compiles Orthanc from source. Looking through the compilation instructions and inspired by the official docker images I have assembled the following Dockerfile:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock Mac with Apple Watch stopped working</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/06/17/unlock-mac-with-apple-watch-stopped-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 13:37:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/06/17/unlock-mac-with-apple-watch-stopped-working/</guid>
      <description>Occasionally my auto unlock Mac with Apple watch stops working. There are workaround instructions to &amp;ldquo;repair&amp;rdquo; this issue. One of them involves rebooting both Mac and Apple Watch. Just like you I&amp;rsquo;m not very keen of rebooting my workstation. Deeper into researching I found the unlock feature relies on Bluetooth and Wifi.
So the following steps are needed to reset the auto unlock:
 Open System Preferences Go to Security &amp;amp; Privacy Go to General Uncheck Allow your Apple Watch to unlock your Mac (Step 1) Turn off Bluetooth and then turn it on again (Step 2) Turn off WiFi and then turn it on again (Step 3)  After that turn on auto unlock again:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debug shell script error: not found</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/05/29/debug-shell-script-error-not-found/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 00:13:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/05/29/debug-shell-script-error-not-found/</guid>
      <description>Automation engineers often have boring tasks. Their job is to automate repetitive tasks. In the early days of Unix and Linux most automation is done with shell scripts. Nowadays we use higher level configuration management systems like Ansible, Puppet, Salt, etc replacing most of the erroneous scripts with poor error handling, lots of boiler code and more importantly high maintenance cost.
$ ./main.sh ./main.sh: 3: exec: ./external.sh: not found $ ls -l -rwxr-xr-x 1 xiwen xiwen 33 May 29 01:25 external.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple high value tests with Python Flask</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/05/05/simple-high-value-tests-with-python-flask/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 01:11:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/05/05/simple-high-value-tests-with-python-flask/</guid>
      <description>After 6 years developing Python Flask applications, mainly REST API&amp;rsquo;s, in 2019 I still could not find any good articles about how to develop high value tests for Python Flask based applications. That is going to change today!
First I will give my opinion on testing and methodology, followed by a demo case to illustrate high value testing with actual code. Feel free to skip all the boring reading and head directly over to the code on Github.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
