<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>osx on CINAQ</title>
    <link>/tags/osx/</link>
    <description>Recent content in osx on CINAQ</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 13:37:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/osx/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mysterious Ipad screen mirror app detected by PSI Secure browser</title>
      <link>/blog/2022/08/28/mysterious-ipad-screen-mirror-app-detected-by-psi-secure-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 13:37:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022/08/28/mysterious-ipad-screen-mirror-app-detected-by-psi-secure-browser/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re in a rush for the solution, jump to the bottom of this page.
 Recently I had my CKS (Certified Kubernetes Security Specialist) exam via the PSI platform. A few weeks earlier when I scheduled the exam I made sure to run the system check because I had troubles with these in the past with my macbook (OSX). I don&amp;rsquo;t recall which exam platform it was.
10 minutes before the scheduled exam I opened the PSI portal to start the check-in process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock Mac with Apple Watch stopped working</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/06/17/unlock-mac-with-apple-watch-stopped-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 13:37:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/06/17/unlock-mac-with-apple-watch-stopped-working/</guid>
      <description>Occasionally my auto unlock Mac with Apple watch stops working. There are workaround instructions to &amp;ldquo;repair&amp;rdquo; this issue. One of them involves rebooting both Mac and Apple Watch. Just like you I&amp;rsquo;m not very keen of rebooting my workstation. Deeper into researching I found the unlock feature relies on Bluetooth and Wifi.
So the following steps are needed to reset the auto unlock:
 Open System Preferences Go to Security &amp;amp; Privacy Go to General Uncheck Allow your Apple Watch to unlock your Mac (Step 1) Turn off Bluetooth and then turn it on again (Step 2) Turn off WiFi and then turn it on again (Step 3)  After that turn on auto unlock again:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
